A Guide to the H. Mitchell Meyer Papers, 1959-1988
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
H. Mitchell Meyers Papers 1959-1988
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
M265
.33 linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated to Special Collections and Archives by Celia Meyer in May 1989.
Biographical Information
H. Mitchell Meyer was born circa 1902 in Richmond, Virginia. He graduated from the University of Virginia and received a law degree from the University of Richmond. He completed a post graduate study at Harvard Law School and Columbia University. He operated Meyer's Dry Goods Store on Hull Street from the early 1920's until 1956, when he began taking summer art classes at the Skowhegan School of Art in Maine. He and his wife were the first persons to participate in a VCU program allowing senior citizens to take free classes. At age 60, he graduated with a master of fine arts degree and began teaching history at VCU. He participated in a number of art shows and won several awards. He designed his own home and sculpture garden and was a member and past president of the Richmond Artists' Association. He was also a past president of the South Richmond Optimist Club.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1959-1988, of H. Mitchell Meyer consisting of documents relating to the Federal Arts Council of Richmond, his class notes, and sketches and prints.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Class-related items, 1963-1968 (Folder 1)
- Federal Arts Council of Richmond, 1973-1975 (Folder 2)
- Newspaper clippings and exhibit brochures, 1959-1988 (Folder 3)
- Notes, n.d. (Folder 4)
- Notes, n.d. (Folder 5)
- Notes, n.d. (Folder 6)
- Notes, n.d. (Folder 7)
- One Man Show at Lynchburg Fine Arts Center, 1963 (Folder 8)
- Prints, n.d. (Folder 9)
- Sketches, n.d. (Folder 10)
- Sketchbook, n.d. (Folder 11)
- Prints, 1960. (Folder 1)
- Sketches, paintings, photographs, 1960-1974. (Folder 2)